Ralph Ramos

Las Vegas, NV, 89032 | 702-460-2797 ralphramos702@gmail.com

Dependable and goal-oriented IT Specialist early in his career who is accustomed to providing the highest degree of in-person, and remote support to Clients. Strive to provide the highest customer service possible, including exceptional IT support that allows the company to view IT as a competitive asset rather than an overhead cost.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) - Information Technology

Western Governors University, Millcreek, UT

GPA: 3.56

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA A+, Network+, Security+, Project+. **AWS** Certified Cloud Practitioner. **LPI** Linux Essentials. **ITIL Foundation.**

EXPERIENCE

IT Technician Mar 2021 - Present

Las Vegas Paiute Tribe, Las Vegas, NV

- Diagnose, repair, and maintain hardware and software components to ensure the smooth running of computer systems.
- Assist new hires during the onboarding process to ensure their IT issued equipment functions as planned.
- Responding to ticket queries with Zendesk either in person, on the phone, chat or via email.
- Replacing and cloning Hard Drives to Solid State Drives.
- Mapped drives to employees to access resources shared on a local network.
- Diagnose and set up printers with scans folders for new employees.
- Manage security policies and protection through Sophos Central.
- Updated new Windows Server, migrated all files and joined users to the new domain.

Help Desk Technician

Feb 2021 - Apr 2021

Arma Global, Remote, FL

- Developed an understanding of usage with Freshdesk ticketing system.
- Monitor incoming service desk tickets, track incidents, and troubleshoot issues.
- Conduct troubleshooting issues to resolve IT-related and application issues for 300+ users.
- Provide clients with information on available upgrades and troubleshoot computer related problems.
- Create and manage end user accounts using Active Directory.

Lab Assistant Feb 2016 - Mar 2021

LMC Aurora Diagnostic, Las Vegas, NV

- Established an understanding of Laboratory Information System while providing technical system support and help to the Pathologist on site. (15% increase on turnaround time)
- Efficiently recorded, evaluated, and managed patient information into the electronic medical record system in a timely manner. (minimized information errors for the year by 25%)
- Comply with the correct procedures, policies, and health and safety regulations.
- Keep laboratory supplies accurate by inventory, placing orders and verifying receipt.

Valet Attendant Dec 2014 - Feb 2016

Trump Hotel, Las Vegas, NV

- Developed a relationship with hotel guests while anticipating their needs and providing support while resolving any issue. (contributed to a 30% increase of likeliness for guest to return)
- Greet all guests in a courteous, friendly, and professional manner while providing assistant.
- Answer guest questions about hotel amenities and provide information and support about local businesses or attractions that may be of interest. (handle 50+ customer interactions per day, giving detailed, personalized, friendly & polite service to ensure customer retention)